我叫巴里·艾伦
My name is Barry Allen,
是现今世上速度最快的人
and I am the fastest man alive.
在外人看来  我只是个普通的鉴证专员
To the outside world, I am an ordinary forensic scientist.
但在尖端科研实验室的朋友们的帮助下
but secretly, with the help of my friends at S.T.A.R. Labs,
我秘密地打击犯罪  寻找跟我一样的超能力者
I fight crime and find other meta-humans like me.
但是我在时间中迷失了
But I became lost in time.
我的朋友们用尽了一切办法才把我救回来
It took everything in my friends' power to bring me back.
但我们的世界也因此出现了新的威胁
and in doing so our world was opened up to new threats.
我是唯一来得及阻止他们的人
And I'm the only one fast enough to stop them.
我是闪电侠
I am the Flash.
《闪电侠》前情回顾
Previously, on "The Flash"...
事情将会发生调整  让闪电侠队
Events will align that allow Team Flash
有机会发现你的身份
a chance to discover your identity.
没关系
It is of no concern.
我就能得出一套预测算法
I could whip up a predictive algorithm.
对  对
Jah, jah, jah.
然后在我的量子大脑芯片里运行这套算法
Run it through my quantum cerebral chip,
我们就能马上找到他
we'll find them in no time.
如果你计算错误即使是一个小数点
If you've miscalculated by even a decimal--
没有小数点  也没有分数
There is not a decimal, a fraction,
没有无穷小变量能躲过我的思维
an infinitesimal variable beyond my thought.
我们要找的人叫克利福德·迪沃
The name we're looking for is Clifford DeVoe.
与我们的心理侧写百分之九十二吻合
92% match to our psychological profile,
克利福德·迪沃
没有其他叫迪沃的更接近了
No other DeVoe comes close.
有什么可以效劳的吗
Can I help you?
我们想跟克利福德·迪沃聊聊
We were just hoping to talk with Clifford DeVoe.
他在家吗
Is he here?
下午好  先生们
Good afternoon, gentlemen.
有什么能效劳的吗
How may I be of help?
中城大学
道教
Effects...
四年前
的
Of...
影响
Taoism.
好了  同学们
All right, class.
论文主题
你们的论文  以这些为主题
Write your, essays on... this list of topics.
给你们两周的时间
You have two weeks to complete them.
哪位同学有之前的笔记吗
Does-- does anyone have their notes from earlier?
我好像认不出自己写的东西了
I'm afraid I can't read my own handwriting.
下课
Class dismissed.
我知道这个表情
I know that look.
11点的"流体力学和物理热力学简介"
I felt the same after my 11:00 A.M.
下课之后我也是这个表情
"Introduction to Fluid Mechanics and Physical Thermodynamics" class.
我是想解释湍流的流速
See, I was trying to explain the turbulent flow rates,
可是十分钟后  我就抓狂了
and ten minutes in, I wanted to pull my hair out.
还好我知道水向管轴流动叫
It's a good thing I know water flowing to the axis of a tube is called...
-你最好别说错  -层流
- You better get this right. - Laminar?
看来你认真听讲了
So you do listen.
你的课必须的
To you, always.
如果讲的课不像视频网站上
Nothing matters to them if it's not digestible
无聊视频那样浅显易懂  他们就听不进去
in YouTube videos of talking babies or inane pet tricks.
你看过哈士奇唱《宛如处女》[麦当娜名曲]
Have you seen the husky singing "Like a Virgin""
我让你笑了
I made you smile.
他们智力不够领会知识的馈赠
How can we enlighten them if their minds are too small
那要怎么才能启发他们呢
to handle the gift of knowledge anymore?
你的方案会奏效的
Your plan will work.
我们只是需要重新设计授课的方法
We just need to refashion the delivery system.
不是方案有问题
It's not the plan that's flawed,
是我的执行能力有问题
it's my ability to execute it.
克利福德
Clifford.
我不够聪明
I'm simply not smart enough.
你是我认识的最聪明的人了
You are the most brilliant mind I know.
还不够
It's not enough.
目前不够
Not yet.
那要何时
When?
现在还只是个概念
At this point, it's just a concept.
我把它称为思考帽
I call this my thinking cap.
就像他们的智力不够
And just like their minds
无法掌握全部的知识
have gotten too small to handle their full capacity,
而我的不足以教会他们
mine's too small to deliver it.
这个东西可以改变一切
This can change all that,
当然要先造出来
if you build it, of course.
你的梦想就是我的梦想
Your dream is my dream.
你所热爱的也是我热爱的
And your passion is my passion.
没有你我什么都不是
I'm nothing without you.
不是太甜吧
I hope it's not too sweet.
太棒了
This is amazing.
我妻子也是如此
Just like my wife.
不仅能抽出时间来照顾我
Somehow she finds time to take care of me
还能把家务做得有声有色
and still keep an immaculate household.
她做的三层芝士通心粉  天下无敌
And her three-cheese macaroni? Second to none!
有时我觉得我是世界上最幸运的男人
Sometimes I think I'm the luckiest man alive.
先生们  有什么事
Gentlemen, how can I help?
我们在调查过程中遇到了迪沃这个名字
The name DeVoe came up in an investigation of ours.
如果不介意  我们想问你几个问题
We would just like to ask you some questions, if that's okay.
为什么找他
Why him?
迪沃是个很常见的名字
DeVoe's a common name.
是的  我猜光是中城地区
Yes, I'd wager at least 1,100 individuals
差不多至少有1100人
give or take a few with that last name
都是姓迪沃的
in the Central City area alone.
该名字已经被确认
The name's been identified
与四个单独的刑事案件有关
for its connection to four separate criminal cases.
你们认为我丈夫是这些案件的目击证人吗
So you think my husband is a witness to these crimes?
不  我们认为他是嫌犯
No, we'd like to eliminate him as a suspect.
你们开玩笑吧
You can't be serious.
没事  马尔利泽  请继续
That's all right, Marlize. Do go ahead.
教授  你为什么会来到中城
So, Professor, what brought you to Central City?
我在南非长大  在南非约翰内斯堡大学
I grew up in South Africa. After studying history
学习了历史和计量经济学之后
and econometrics at the University of Johannesburg,
在牛津大学任教
I took a teaching position at Oxford.
我们就是在那认识的
That's where we met.
自从他让我神魂颠倒之后  我们就在一起了
He swept me off my feet and we have been together ever since.
中城大学的确用终身职位
It did take a tenured offer from Central City University
才引诱我离开牛津大学
to lure me away from the Oxford faculty.
那是四年前的事了
That was four years ago.
我想问问  你认识拉姆齐·迪肯吗
Question: Do you know Ramsey Deacon?
不  我该认识吗
No, should I?
那贝琪·夏普呢
What about Becky Sharpe?
我恐怕也不认识
No, I'm afraid not.
拉尔夫·德比
Ralph Dibny?
米娜·沙伊唐
Mina Chaytan?
米娜·沙伊唐  这名字听着很熟
Mina Chaytan. Now, that name's familiar.
她不就是那个突然离开的印第安女人吗
Isn't this the Native American woman that left abruptly?
-那个人类学家  -对  我记得
- You know, the anthropologist? - Yes, I remember.
她的离开让我很难受
I was so sad to see her go.
你们是同事
You were colleagues.
她有提到过她的研究吗
Did she mention her work?
没有  米娜是有朝气的女人
No, no, no. Mina was an animated woman.
再说  我们这样的人把教育视为使命
Then again, people like us who see education as a calling,
我们经常这样
we often are.
那幅画
That painting...
很漂亮
Uh, it's beautiful.
武士是可怕的敌人
The samurai. They were formidable foes.
对其敌人来说  他们经常势不可挡
They'd often make unstoppable enemies to their opponents.
你可不想遇到他们
You wouldn't want to cross one.
那你在日本待过吗
So you spent time in Japan?
日本中世纪的封建历史
The feudal history of medieval Japan
是我的研究领域之一
is one of my areas of expertise.
那你肯定会说日语
Then you must speak the language?
是  我一心只想搞学问
Hai, watashi wa gakumon-kaide shika shiyo shite imasen.
他还会说法语  意大利语  中文
He also speaks French, Italian, Mandarin,
还有其他几种语言
and several other languages.
是这样的  是这样的
Here's the thing, here's the thing.
我很喜欢教书
I love teaching.
教书让我有机会开拓视野
It gives me the opportunity to broaden perspectives.
但是不能单单鼓励人们变得更好
But you can't just inspire people to be better.
而是要改变他们思考的方式
You somehow need to change the way people think.
克利福德  我丈夫非常有激情
Clifford! My husband is very passionate,
但他也需要休息
but he also needs his rest.
我们还有什么能帮忙的吗
Is there anything else we can do to help?
没有了  谢谢
No. Thank you.
如果我们再有问题  我们会联系你们的
If we have any more questions, we'll get in contact.
-巴里  -好
- Barry. - Yeah.
你知道我在哪
You know where to find me.
怎么样
Well?
是他吗
Is it him?
闪 电 侠
第四季
第七集
中城大学
克利福德·迪沃
我说不好  巴里
I don't know, Barry.
这位腼腆的大学教授就像是奶酪通心粉
This shy college professor who likes mac 'n' cheese
我不觉得他像是犯罪主谋
doesn't exactly seem like a criminal mastermind to me.
拜托  这已经不是第一回了
I mean, come on. It wouldn't be the first time
人们假装友善
somebody played nice
最后确是我们要抓的坏人
and then turned out to be our bad guy.
威尔斯委员会提到他肯定是有原因的
The Council of Wells gave us his name for a reason.
-他是从  -1100人当中提到的他
- He gave us one name out of-- - 1,100.
准确说是1122人
1,122 to be precise.
22个人的误差
He was off by 22.
这不是有点可疑吗
I mean, isn't that a little suspicious?
除非他上网搜过自己
Not if he Googled himself.
我只是说这家伙有些不对劲
I'm just saying there's something weird about this guy.
他喜欢武士
He likes samurai!
谁不喜欢啊
Who doesn't?
你看过《座头市》
Have you seen "Zatoichi"--
"盲剑客"吗
"The Blind Swordsman?"
-最好的标准收藏版  -最好的套装
- Best Criterion Collection... - Great box set.
-史上最好  -别跑题
- Ever. - Okay, guys.
想想看
Think about this:
如果委员会没错  就是说是
If the Council's right, that means DeVoe
迪沃刻意安排我逃脱神速力
arranged for me to come out of the Speed Force
回到这里  连你都做不到
exactly where he wanted. Even you couldn't do that.
你说到重点了
You have a point.
好吧  我们开始分工协作吧
Okay, let's cover all our bases.
同意
Agreed.
西斯科  哈里  要不要看看
Okay, Cisco, Harry, you guys want to see what kind
能从他上找出什么数据痕迹
of digital footprint you can get on this guy?
好
Yeah.
凯特林  你有朋友在中城大学
Caitlin, you've got friends at CCU.
我们来看看要对付的是什么人吧
Let's see what kind of person we're dealing with.
好的
Will do.
老爸  去中城警局查查他的背景
Dad, CCPD background check?
马上去  亲爱的
On it, sweet one.
还有你  你还好吧
And you. You all right?
挺好的  谢谢你的关心
Yeah, but thank you for asking.
你知道吗  我觉得人事估计不会
Ooh, you know, I think Human Resources might not be
认同咱们  毕竟是工作同事
okay with this, us being coworkers and all.
我觉得他们会睁一眼闭一眼的
Yeah, I think they'll let it slide,
毕竟我一周后就要和梦中同事
considering I get to marry the coworker of my dreams
结婚了
a week from now.
你知道有时候我感觉像...
You know sometimes I feel like...
像什么
Like what?
像是世上最幸福的人
Like I'm the luckiest man alive.
核子物理  凝聚态宇宙学
Nuclear physics, condensed matter cosmology,
四年前
相对论  所有这些领域
even relativity, all these fields
都会在一夜之间被颠覆
will be revolutionized overnight.
你在我的发明中注入了生命
You've infused my design with life.
咱们还有个问题
We still have a problem.
现在没有办法启动
There's currently no way to power a prototype
这么复杂的原型
this sophisticated.
咱们会找到办法的
We'll find a solution.
无限扩展大脑的能力
Expanding the mind to an infinite capacity requires
需要庞大的能量来源
an expanding energy source.
咱们要去哪找这种量级的能量
Where are we going to find that kind of power?
-能告诉我们如何做到吗  -开大点声
- Can you tell us how? - Turn that up.
它会改变我们对科学的看法
It'll change the way we think about science.
关于量子力学
About quantum mechanics,
关于分子物理学
about molecular physics.
粒子加速器本周开启
只要我的粒子加速器上线
Once my particle accelerator goes online,
将会炸断捆绑科学大门的锁链
it'll blow the doors of science off their hinges.
真不可思议
That's amazing.
我们需要一个超乎想像的能量来源
We needed a power source unlike anything imaginable.
看来哈里森·威尔斯已经帮咱们想出来了
Well, it seems Harrison Wells just imagined it for us.
一瞬间改变人生
Instantly change lives.
历史的进程就像个圆环
History moves in cycles.
因此我们必须学习前车之鉴
We must therefore learn from what came before us
以此来开辟一条道路
in order to carve a path
免去后顾之忧
for what's to come.
因为那些不懂得学习...
Because those who don't learn from--
因为那些不懂的学习历史教训的人
Because those who don't learn from history
必然会重蹈覆辙
are doomed to repeat it.
下课了
Class dismissed.
别忘了你们的阅读材料
Don't forget your reading material!
反主流文化的第十一章
Chapter 11 on the counterculture backlash
以及它对里根政府的影响
and its influence on the Reagan administration.
艾伦先生
Mr. Allen.
一天碰到你两次
Twice in one day.
是啊  抱歉又要打扰你了
Yeah, sorry to bother you again.
我可是有一大摞期中考试卷子
Look, I do have a stack of midterm exams--
是  我知道你很忙
Yeah, no, I understand you're busy.
这不会太耗时间的  我就是想问一下
This won't take long. I just wanted to ask,
四年前1月7日那晚
where were you four years ago
你当时在什么地方
on the night of January 7th?
说实话  艾伦先生  我不知道
Honestly, Mr. Allen, I have no idea.
你这调查要回顾到多久之前
How far back does this investigation of yours go?
这个我不能和你透露
I'm not at liberty to discuss that with you.
还有  你乘公共交通吗
Also, um, do you ever use public transit?
什么  地铁一类的吗
What? Like the subway?
你想像一下我这轮椅...
I mean imagine me in a wheelchair--
我是指公交车
More like a bus.
有必要这样吗
Is this really necessary?
我只是想周密一些
I'm just being thorough.
行  我比较喜欢用来福打车
Fine. I prefer Lyft.
对轮椅用户比较友好
They're wheelchair friendly.
说实话  艾伦先生  我的出行车辆选择
Honestly, Mr. Allen, how are my vehicle options important
或是一个我记不清楚的日期很重要吗
or a date I can hardly remember?
我只是想拼凑起一个时间线
I'm just trying to establish a timeline,
解决谜团
solve a mystery.
神秘是给小说家和考古学家准备的
Mysteries are for novelists and archeologists.
你应该做的是将我从嫌犯中剔除
You were supposed to be ruling me out as a suspect.
但你反而看起来像是抓到了人一样
Instead it seems like you've got your guy.
不  这只是例行程序
Oh, no. This is just procedure.
感觉像是迫害
Feels like persecution.
现在  我是再联络你
Now, can I get back to you,
还是说我要和你走一趟
or do I need to accompany you downtown?
不  当然不用
No, of course not.
给我发邮件就行
Just e-mail me.
再一次的  抱歉打扰你了
And again, I'm sorry to bother you.
这个是超能力者的DNA
So this is an example of meta-DNA.
这是你带来的迪沃DNA
This is the DNA you brought me from DeVoe.
完全是普通人
It's completely normal.
你看到这些不同了吗
Do you see all the differences?
克利福德·迪沃不是超能力者
Clifford DeVoe is not a meta.
你俩有什么发现吗
Did you two find anything?
他从来没被逮捕过
Well, he's never been arrested,
他按时交税负和贷款
he pays all his taxes and his mortgage.
他有个很不错的401K计划[养老金]
He has a very reasonable 401k plan.
给山峦协会[环保组织]捐款
Donates to the Sierra Club,
在孤儿院当义工教官
volunteers at an orphanage as a big brother.
爸爸也没找到什么
Dad didn't find anything either.
说他是社区里非常正直的一员
Says that he's an upstanding member of the community.
我和牛津大学的一些朋友谈了谈
Yeah, I talked to some friends at Oxford.
他们说迪沃有些茫然
They said DeVoe's a little absentminded,
但是大家都喜欢他
but everybody likes him.
各位  我告诉你们
Guys, I'm telling you.
克利福德·迪沃可不是表面那样
Clifford DeVoe is not what he seems.
你可能只是受了轮椅的影响
That could just be the wheelchair.
-我是说...  -才没有
- I mean-- - No.
你这方面确实有一段黑历史
You do kind of have a bad history.
那不是我
That wasn't me.
得了吧  他简直太完美了
Come on. He's just too perfect.
好吗  我有个强烈的感觉
Okay? I just--I have a strong feeling
他在隐藏些什么
that he's hiding something.
你们不信我
You don't believe me.
不是我们不信你  巴里
No, it's not that we don't believe you, Barry.
只是  现在迪沃看起来是个好人
It's just, right now DeVoe seems like a good guy.
各位  就是他
Guys, it's him.
我还以为我们不会再先入为主假设别人是坏蛋了
I thought we were done just assuming people are villains.
好吧  告诉你们
All right, you know what?
震波一下
Vibe it.
我的天
Oh, my God.
你说得对
You were right.
那个奶酪通心粉看着难以置信地好吃
That mac 'n' cheese looks unbelievable.
你看  这听着可不怎么像坏蛋是吧
See? That doesn't sound very villainous, does it?
巴里  能出来跟你说几句吗
Barry, can I talk to you outside?
好了  你要不要告诉我真正困扰你的是什么
Okay, so do you want to tell me what's really bothering you?
我的直觉强烈得要爆表了
My Spidey sense is just tingling way off the charts.
巴里  这有没有可能是因为
But, Barry, is there any chance that this
我们的婚礼呢
is about the wedding?
或许你感觉有一点...
I mean maybe you're feeling a little--
不  我没有紧张
No, I'm not nervous.
但你的表现和平常可不一样
But you're not acting the way that you normally do.
萨维塔和魔术师警告过我们
Look, Savitar and Kadabra warned us
有关一个叫迪沃的人
about someone named DeVoe.
这个叫迪沃的可能是所有事的幕后黑手
This DeVoe guy could be behind everything.
公交车上的超能力者
The bus metas,
我在错误的地点使出了神速力
me coming out of the Speed Force at the wrong place,
还有机士
the Samuroid!
巴里  有没有可能是你太执着于
Barry, is there a possibility that you were so determined
找出坏人  提前做好准备
to find the bad guy and get ahead of everything
以至于你只能以你想要的角度
that you're seeing things exactly the way
看待所有的事
you want to see them?
没有  我...
No. I...
或许吧  我不知道...
Maybe, I don't...
听着  七天之后
Look, in seven days
我就要嫁给我爱的男人了
I am going to marry the man that I love.
但现在我得找一位新的DJ了
But right now I have to lock down a new DJ
上一位因为喝得太多
because the last one got fired for drinking too much
一直在和新娘的父亲跳舞  所以被辞退了
and wouldn't stop dancing with the father of the bride.
其实乔可能还挺开心的
Joe might be into that, actually.
所以我才需要回家
Which is exactly why I need to go home.
我很希望你能帮我
And I would really like your help.
准备好参加记者招待会了吗
Ready for the press conference?
当然了
Absolutely.
谢谢  我是哈里森·威尔斯
Thank you. My name is Harrison Wells.
未来  从今晚开始
Tonight, the future begins.
我和我的队伍将要在这里做的工作
The work my team and I will do here
会改变我们对物理的理解
will change our understanding of physics,
会带来能源上的进步
will bring about advancements in power,
医疗上的进步
advancements in medicine.
总之就是会带来进步
It'll bring about advancements, period.
这就是未来
This is the future.
相信我
And trust me,
未来的到来比你们想的要快
it'll be here faster than you think.
这对你有什么意义
What does it mean to you?
我们的新的努力...
This new endeavor of ours--
我的笔记本电脑  里面有我的论文
Hey, my laptop! It's got my dissertation!
为了中城的市民们
For the citizens of Central City.
看来今晚的娱乐活动
Well, it would appear tonight's entertainment
不只局限在舞台上
is not limited to the stage.
加速器上线之后
What's the first thing you'll do
你要做的第一件事是什么
once the accelerator is online?
和我的队员们一起开一瓶昂贵的唐培里侬香槟
Is crack open an expensive bottle of Dom Perignon
因为我对他们催得很紧
with my staff, because I ride them very hard
他们值得喝上好香槟  请讲
and they've earned it. Yes?
那些反对加速器的人认为
Those protesting this accelerator
加速器会在中城里制造一个黑洞
believe it could open a black hole in Central City.
但加速器是否更有可能产生更好的现象
But is it not more likely to cause a benevolent phenomenon
比如希格斯玻色子桥
like a Higgs boson bridge?
今晚唯一会发生的现象
The only phenomenon that will occur this evening
我们已经精确计算到了每一个细节
is one that has been calculated to the tiniest detail,
精确到每一个小数点
to the tiniest decimal point.
就是说你预见到了每一种可能性
So you've foreseen every possible outcome?
是的  您是...
Yes, I have, Miss...?
马尔利泽·迪沃夫人
Mrs. Marlize DeVoe.
迪沃
DeVoe.
那么你身边的那位先生
I expect that would make the gentleman
想必就是你的丈夫了
to your right your husband?
克利福德·迪沃
Clifford DeVoe.
我非常喜欢你们的成果
I'm a big fan of your work.
先生  我相信你们的成果
Sir, I believe it will have
会对未来产生巨大的影响
an enormous impact on our future.
谢谢你们能来  教授
Thank you for coming, Professor.
祝你好运
Good luck.
停下
关上它
Shut it down!
威尔斯在说谎  他知道加速器不会成功
Wells is lying. He knows the accelerator won't succeed.
他会愿意冒着爆炸的风险吗
He'd risk an explosion?
不  我觉得他就是想要一场爆炸
No, I think he wants one,
只有暗物质的放射性尘埃
only the fallout from dark matter
被释放到大气中
being released into the atmosphere
才能产生我们尚未预测到的变量
will produce variants we cannot yet predict.
我们必须推迟计划
We need to delay our plan.
不  这样更好
No, this is even better.
我们会得到所需的全部能量
We'll have all the power we need.
不行  太冒险了
No! It's too risky.
我倒是愿意赌一把
I'm willing to take the chance.
只有这场爆炸能给帽子提供能量
The blast is the only thing that can power the cap.
我们该等等  试试找到别的方法
We should wait. Try and find another way.
这是唯一的办法
This is the only way.
关上它  关上它
Shut it down! Shut it down!
关上它
Shut it down!
关上它  关上它
Shut it down! Shut it down!
能量水平
准备好了吗  亲爱的
Ready, my love?
已经就位
In position!
开始了
It's starting!
怎么回事
What's happening?
克利福德
Clifford!
不
No!
克利福德  不  不  不
Clifford, no! No! No!
你竟敢抛下我
Don't you dare leave me!
还以为我要失去你了
I thought I'd lost you.
你感觉怎么样
How do you feel?
大受启发
Enlightened.
艾伦
Hey, Allen!
-辛格想见你  -稍等
- Singh wants to see you. - One second.
还是别了艾伦  辛格又摆出那张臭脸了
I don't know, Allen. Singh's making that face again.
你最好还是快点
You might want to hurry.
相信我  我明白  艾伦先生
Trust me, I understand. Mr. Allen!
这是什么
What's this?
-请关上门  -好
- Close the door, please. - Yeah.
请继续  教授
Continue, Professor.
先是我家  然后是我的教室
First my home, then my classroom.
下一个是哪里  我们睡觉的卧室吗
What's next? Our bedroom where we sleep?
我和乔只是去...
Joe and I just went--
我代表中城警局
On behalf of the Central City Police Department,
对这次闯入表示
I'd like to extend our sincerest apologies
真诚的歉意
for this intrusion.
艾伦先生
Mr. Allen?
好吧  很抱歉打扰您  迪沃先生
Um, yeah. I'm sorry for disturbing you, Mr. DeVoe.
是迪沃教授
Professor DeVoe.
谢谢你们来访
Thank you for coming in.
他们来这儿到底要干什么
What the hell were they doing here?
只是填了份投诉你的表格
They just filed a complaint against you.
说你骚扰了他们
Said you harassed them.
我才没有骚扰他们
No, I wasn't harassing them.
你到底为什么去烦他们啊
Why are you bothering them at all?
-我...  -是我们正在查的一件案子
- I-- - It's a case we're working on.
什么案子
What case?
是一个...
It's something that--
帮我个忙
Do me a favor.
离那位好教授和他妻子远一点
Stay away from the nice professor and his wife.
-队长  迪沃看起来非常...  -什么
- Captain, DeVoe seems very-- - Very what?
除非答案是犯下了非常严重的罪行
And unless the answer is guilty of a very specific crime,
否则你就大错特错了
you are way off base.
你也是  乔  你应该比他清楚
So are you, Joe. You should know better than that.
你不能突然闯进别人的家里
You don't show up at someone's house
就开始问问题
and start asking questions.
你得遵守规则
You follow protocol.
是  长官
Yes, sir.
有人在家吗
Anybody home?
爸爸说你今天过得很不好
Hi. Dad said you were having a bad day.
什么  没有  我很好
What? No, I'm fine.
应该说我好极了  你怎么样
I'm great, actually. How are you doing?
什么
What?
你在干...
What are you--
这是什么
What is this?
他的妻子爱瑞丝在帮他
His wife, Iris, she's helping him.
不  听着  好  你看
No, listen! Okay, look:
她可不是长相漂亮贤良淑德的家庭主妇
She's not Suzy Homemaker with her perfect mac 'n' cheese.
她是位贤妻良母
She is a Stepford wife.
她有两个博士学位
She's got two doctorates, you know?
一个机械工程学的
One in mechanical engineering
一个高级机器人学的
and another in advanced robotics.
他们就是这么分工的
That's how they work!
丈夫制定计划  妻子来实施计划
He comes up with the plans, but she executes them.
她算得上是机械天才了
She's some kind of mechanical genius.
那你是觉得迪沃和他妻子是超级大坏蛋
So you think that DeVoe and his wife are supervillains?
-是  -听听你说的话吧  巴里
- Yes. - Listen to yourself, Barry.
怎么了
What?
迪沃已经填了文件投诉你了
DeVoe has already filed a complaint against you!
我知道  我...
I know, I--
听着  西斯科  哈里  我爸爸  凯特琳
Look, Cisco, Harry, my dad, Caitlin,
他们都是厉害的人  但在迪沃身上一无所获
they are the best, and they have found nothing on DeVoe.
我们一周后就要结婚了  巴里
We are getting married in a week, Barry.
求你了
Please,
为了你的工作和我的幸福着想
for the sake of your job and my sanity,
拜托别管了
please let it go.
我解出来了
I've solved them.
解出了什么
Solved what?
黎曼假说
Riemann's hypothesis,
希尔伯特的第15大问题
Hilbert's 15th problem,
关于代数圈的标准猜想
standard conjectures on algebraic cycles,
还有更多问题
and the list goes on.
克利福德  简直不可思议
Clifford, this-- this is incredible!
随便问我个问题
Ask me anything!
谁是开膛手杰克
Who was Jack the Ripper?
普遍认为是某个叫艾伦·柯明斯基的
The prevailing theory is there was a London barber
伦敦理发师犯下了种种罪行
by the name Aaron Kosminski who committed the crimes.
他也有精神分裂症和妄想症倾向
He also suffered schizophrenic and delusional tendencies.
但是他在科尔尼·哈奇庇护所的护工
But it was his nurse at the Colney Hatch Asylum!
凯瑟琳·珠儿
Catharine Jewell!
我的大脑里好像装满了
It's like every little bit of knowledge
各种各样的知识
now resides inside my brain.
我知道所有能想到的问题的答案
I know every answer to every question ever asked.
你太不可思议了
You're incredible!
我们太不可思议了  你让这一切变为可能
We're incredible! You made all of this possible!
我们终于有办法让世界...
We now finally have the means to bring to the world the--
克利福德  你没事吧
Clifford, are you okay?
克利福德  克利福德
Clifford! Clifford!
克利福德
Clifford!
受害者
你隐瞒了什么  迪沃
What are you hiding, DeVoe?
想像你的身体是条河
Imagine your body as a river.
有一个大坝阻拦了你的双腿
There's a dam blocking your legs.
我的腓肠肌在萎缩  对吗
My gastrocnemius muscles are degenerating, aren't they?
对
Well, yes.
症状类似于...
The symptoms are similar to--
肌萎缩性侧索硬化症
Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis.
但你的肌肉比典型的
But your muscles are decaying faster
渐冻症萎缩得更快更迅速
and more rapidly than typical ALS.
我觉得应该另有原因
I believe this is something else.
所以你的医疗诊断
Is that your medical diagnosis
就是我的病情另有原因
that I have a case of something else?
只是我们从没遇到你这种
It's just we've never seen a case like--oh--
病例
yours before.
复合束颤电位的增强能解释
An increase in complex fasciculation potential
轴突膜异常兴奋的原因
explains axonal membrane hyperexcitability.
但这不能...
But it doesn't--
当然了
Of course.
伽玛波的放射性超过了50赫兹
When gamma wave activity exceeds 50 hertz,
我的乙酰胆碱受体
my acetylcholine receptors draw away
就会远离我的神经末梢
from my nerve receptors
而不会靠近它们
instead of toward them.
你说你是哪方面的教授来着
What did you say you're a professor of?
历史
History.
他病情发展会怎样
What's his prognosis?
典型肌萎缩性侧索硬化症患者
Life expectancy for typical ALS
大概还能活两到五年
is about two to five years.
从这种时间分布来看  我只有一半的时间
In this chronodispersion, it would be half that.
最先出现的就是全身瘫痪
Complete paralysis will come first.
请让我们单独谈谈
Excuse us, please.
说不通啊
This doesn't make sense.
我的大脑在从身体吸取能量
My mind is drawing energy from my body,
就像寄生虫在吞噬虚弱的宿主
like a parasite feeding on an ailing host.
我们离梦寐以求的一切仅一步之遥
We're so close to everything we've ever dreamed of,
却被这副身躯弄得支离破碎
only for it to be ripped away by this body.
不不不
No, no, no.
我们可以阻止的  克利福德  我决不放弃
We can stop this, Clifford. I'll never give up.
2600个有超能力基因的人
2,600 individuals developed the meta-gene.
用超能力抢珠宝店和引发龙卷风
They use it to rob jewelry stores and summon tornadoes.
而我用超能力拯救人类却遭到诅咒
I use mine to save humanity, and I'm condemned?
我们没料到死亡这么快就来了
Dying wasn't part of our plan.
各位  我在机士头盔里找到个摄像机
Guys, I found a camera in the Samuroid head.
摄像机有什么线索吗
Where did it lead back to?
-你们觉得呢  -迪沃
- Where do you think? - DeVoe!
你通过摄像机锁定了他的电脑网络地址吗
So you pinged the camera to his computer's IP address?
-棒  -没  我
- Good! - Well, no, I--
我没有锁定
I didn't ping it.
那你怎么知道是他
Well then, how'd you figure out it was him?
-那个  -摄像机根本没开
- Well-- - This camera isn't even active.
不  我听到了  有声音
No, I heard it. It was making a noise.
-声音  -对
- A noise? - Yeah.
就在机士头盔里  嗡嗡声
Inside the Samuroid head, it was buzzing,
于是我在头盔里发现了摄像机
and then I found that thing inside!
他监视我们好几周了
He's been watching us for weeks,
我本可以证明的  但他的妻子很快就回来了
and I could've proved it, but his wife came back too soon.
-很快  从哪回来  -不知道
- Too soon? From where? - I don't--
巴里  别跟我说你闯入了他们家
Barry, tell me you did not break into their house.
好吧
Wow. Okay.
好了  各位  是挺不好的
Okay, guys, that sounds bad,
但你们得听我说
you have to listen to me,
这家伙想让我们以为他很谦逊软弱
this guy wants us to think he's unassuming and weak,
但不是  他很强大聪明
but he's not, he is powerful and smart.
他每次都抢先我们一步
And he's been ahead of us every step of the way.
-他现在又抢先了  -冷静 艾伦  冷静
- He's ahead of us right now. - Easy, Allen. Calm down.
-我没事  我没事  -好
- I'm fine. I'm fine. - Okay.
我们只希望你不会
Hey, hey, we just don't want you to do
做出其他让你后悔的事
anything else you regret.
其他事  什么意思  我做了什么
Anything else? What do you mean? What have I done?
首先  私闯民宅
For starters, breaking and entering.
老天  我搞不懂
Oh my God, I don't understand
你们怎么就看不明白
why you don't see what's going on!
很有可能到处都是他的摄像头
He probably has cameras everywhere.
实验室  中城警局
At the lab, at CCPD,
我的意思是他一直在监视我们
I mean he's always watching us!
乔  怎么了
Hey, Joe. What is it?
-我发现了一些事  -最好先别说话
- Hey, I found something. - You better stop.
我一点安全感都没有了  知道吗
I just don't feel safe anymore, you know?
我是说  我以为警察本该是保护民众的
I mean I thought the police were supposed to protect people.
我没对你做什么
I haven't done anything to you.
你闯到我们家里了
You broke into our home!
我们不是坏人  我们不该受这种对待
We're good people. We don't deserve this.
好的  我希望你不要再担心
Okay. I don't want you to worry anymore.
艾伦先生会立即停止这种行为
Mr. Allen will stop all of this immediately.
我向你保证
I assure you.
离我们远点
Stay away from us.
我跟你说过  你要远离那些人
I told you to stay away from those people!
队长  你得听我说
Captain, you have to listen to me.
现在放你两周的假  这不是在请求你
You're taking two weeks off, and that is not a request.
你要让我停职
You're suspending me?
我没逮捕你已经算你走运了
You're lucky I'm not arresting you.
趁这段时间好好想想今后该怎么执法
Use your time away to consider your future in law enforcement.
这是什么
What is this?
限制令
A restraining order.
我必须离克利福德·迪沃160米之外
I have to stay 500 feet away from Clifford DeVoe.
你会这么做吗
And are you going to?
巴里
Barry,
这可不像你  你必须停下来
this is not you. You've got to stop.
-我不能  -不能还是不愿意
- I can't. - You can't or you won't?
我已经分不清了
I don't know anymore.
我面对过很多坏蛋
I've faced a lot of bad guys,
他们会伤害我爱的人
people that would hurt the ones that I love,
毁掉世上所有美好的东西  还不当回事
destroy everything good in the world, and think nothing of it,
但这个人
but this guy,
我感觉比其他所有人加起来都危险
he feels more dangerous than all the others combined.
而我们对他几乎还是一无所知
And we still barely know anything about him.
这让我觉得毛骨悚然  爱瑞丝
It scares the hell out of me, Iris.
巴里  我们一起面对未知有多少次了
Barry, how many times have we been up against the unknown?
-这次不一样  -怎么不一样
- This is different. - How?
我从神速力回来以后
Ever since I came back from the Speed Force,
一直都感到发自内心的快乐
I have been constantly and genuinely happy.
我的朋友们都很安全
My friends are safe.
乔又要当爸爸了
Joe's gonna be a dad again.
下周  我就要和我今生挚爱结婚了
And next week, I get to marry the love of my life.
我现在能失去的东西比从前要多
I have more to lose now than ever before.
是的  但等塞西尔生了宝宝以后呢
Yeah, but what about after Cecile has the baby?
或是等我们结婚以后呢
Or after we get married,
或者  等我们有了第一个宝宝以后呢
or even when we have our first child?
时间越往后  我们能失去的东西
You know as time goes by, there's gonna be even more
就越多
for us to lose.
而那些坏人会一直冲着我们过来
And people are always going to be coming after us.
你的心不能被这种念头占满了
You can't let that consume you,
你必须活在当下
you just have to live in the moment
等遇到事情的时候再去面对它
and face it as it comes.
你怎么做到不害怕的
How are you not scared?
因为我们是闪电侠
Because we're The Flash.
克利福德  克利福德
Clifford? Clifford.
Clifford. Clifford!
离我远点
Get away from me!
我是想帮你
I'm trying to help you.
如果你真的想帮我
If you really wish to help,
那就去修一间颞涡畸变室
construct a temporal vortex distortion chamber
别让我变得这么残暴
and prevent me from ever becoming this atrocity!
这是我们希望的
This is what we wanted.
这是因为我连架子上的书都拿不了
Because I cannot grab a damn book from this shelf!
我到底是什么  马尔利泽
What am I, Marlize?
你是我的丈夫
You are my husband!
你丈夫已经死了
Your husband is gone.
让我死吧
Let me die.
我哪里都不会去
I'm not going anywhere.
这副身体迟早会死亡
This body will expire.
如果有这个  就能继续很长时间
It will last longer with this.
你违反了你的限制令  艾伦先生
You are in violation of your restraining order, Mr. Allen.
是的  你可以打电话报警
Well, you can call the cops.
你是想伤害我吗
Do you intend to harm me?
那请务必告诉我  是什么如此重要
Then pray do tell what is so paramount
让你甘愿冒被监禁的风险
that you'd risk incarceration?
我想看着你的眼睛  问你
I wanted to look you in the eyes and ask--
你到底是谁
who are you really?
那是谁在提问
Who's asking?
巴里·艾伦
Barry Allen?
还是闪电侠
Or the Flash?
-你是怎么  -别这样
- How did you-- - Oh, please.
你的小秘密
Your little secret is one of
是我发现的最兴味索然的
the more underwhelming revelations I have uncovered.
我和你诞生于同一天晚上
I was born on the same evening you were.
1月7日
January 7th,
当晚尖端科研实验室的粒子加速器
the night S.T.A.R. Labs' particle accelerator
改变基因的黑暗物质笼罩了整座中城
bathed Central City in gene-altering dark matter.
我们俩都被闪电击中
We were both struck by lightning.
我知道你受影响了
I knew you were affected.
你的测试为什么没显示你的超能力DNA
How did our test not show your meta-DNA?
一个速度如此快的人  怎么脑子如此慢
For such a fast man, you're rather slow.
我可比你聪明
I'm smarter than you.
你和你的科研小队制订的任何策略
You and your science team have devised no strategy,
采取的任何行动  做出的任何协调
no action, no coordinated effort
都在我的意料之中
for which I'm not already prepared.
机士  公交车上的超能力者
The Samuroid, the bus metas.
是你干的
It was you.
但为什么现在告诉我
But why reveal yourself now?
因为我一点也不怕你
Because I have nothing to fear from you.
是吗  你还是再想想吧
Yeah? Well, I'd think twice about that.
我拥有多元宇宙中
I have a team of some of the smartest minds
最聪明的人组成的队伍
from across the multiverse.
你的威尔斯委员会
Yes, your Council of Wells.
那些家伙们当中
Could any one of those clowns
有人能确定我的超能力吗
identify what my abilities are?
你可以把所有星球上的天才聚到一起
You could gather every genius on every planet,
你还是比不过我
and you still couldn't outthink me.
好多超能力者来捉我
Plenty of metas have come after me,
和我爱的人们
the people that I love.
你知道他们有什么共同点吗
You know the one thing they have in common?
他们都失败了
They failed.
你这些年创造了奇迹
You've done wonders all these years
用最基本的能力揍大猩猩
punching gorillas with rudimentary powers,
追疯子  打冷血人
chasing madmen shooting icicles.
就像是小孩子玩玩具枪
Those were children with play guns.
萨维塔  极速  斯旺
Savitar, Zoom, Thawne.
他们的能力和无穷的思想相比
Their powers are nothing compared to the power
什么也不是
of limitless thought.
那就是你的能力
That's your ability?
粒子加速器增强了你的智力
Your intellect was amplified by the particle accelerator.
你可能是最快的人  艾伦
You may be the fastest man alive, Allen.
我的大脑运转最快
I'm the fastest mind.
所以我们就这样进入了
So this is how we begin whatever twisted game
你计划的变态游戏
you have planned.
不  艾伦先生  你已经输了
No, Mr. Allen. You've already lost,
你甚至还没有意识到
and you never even realized it.
祝你即将到来的婚礼顺利
Congratulations on your upcoming nuptials.
我会想着你的
I'll be thinking of you.
我得告诉你们些事情
There's something I need to tell you.
我见过迪沃了
I confronted DeVoe.
不是吧  巴里  他会害你被捕的
Oh, come on, Barry. He could get you arrested!
不  他不会  他想让我去
No, he won't. He wanted me to come.
你怎么知道
How do you know?
首先  他知道我是闪电侠
Well, for starters, he knows I'm the Flash.
所以一直以来你是对的
So you were right all along.
我们却不相信你
We didn't believe you.
对不起
I'm sorry.
不用  迪沃一直在玩我们
Don't be. DeVoe's been playing all of us.
怎么回事
How?
那是他的超能力
It's his powers.
他的智力高到超出我们的想像
He has an intelligence beyond anything we could've imagined.
他精心策划了我们所碰到的这些事
He's orchestrated everything that we've encountered.
我们就像他的棋子
He's moved us like chess pieces
而我们甚至意识不到自己在游戏中
in a game we didn't even know we were playing.
我们怎么阻止拥有超级智能的人
How do we stop someone who has super intelligence?
我们也很聪明
We're pretty smart.
或许我们并没有
Maybe we're not.
思考着
The Thinker!
很好  恰当的危机感  一个词搞定
It's good. Apt sense of menace. Nailed it in one.
各位  需要我们所有人才能阻止他
Guys, it's gonna take all of us to stop him.
听起来你们需要一臂之力
Sounds like y'all could use a hand.
沃利
Wally!
-见到你真好  儿子  -我也是
- Good to see you, son! - You too.
蓝谷如何
How was Blue Valley?
自我反省  与外太空海星战斗
Self-reflection and a battle with a starfish
能给人不少启发
from outer space gives you perspective.
你发现你要找的了
So you found what you were looking for?
说实话  我不知道
I don't know, to be honest.
很高兴你回来了
Well, we are glad you're home.
看来你们找到了公交超能力者背后的主谋
Looks like you found the guy behind the bus metas.
是的
Yeah.
所以你要穿上战服  干掉他
So you want to suit up? Take him down?
不  现在该他行动
No, now it's his move.
我们不用太心急  制订好计划
I think we take our time, formulate a plan.
接下来呢  老板娘
What now, boss lady?
我们先结婚
We get married.
他来找你  就像你说的他会来
He came to you, just you said he would.
他最终控制了他的恐惧
He's finally seized control of his fear.
他的力量源自
He drew his strength
那群他称作朋友的家伙们
from those he calls friends.
听起来你很欣赏他
Sounds like you admire him.
很有趣
It is fascinating.
在我预测的4900个可能发生的事情
In the chain of 4,900 possible events I predicted,
有一种是他们称我为"老师"
there was one which resulted in them calling me "The Teacher"
我更喜欢"思考者"
I prefer "The Thinker"
他们会是第一批感受到"启蒙"的人
They will be the first to experience the Enlightenment.
你失去连接的时间太久了
You've been unplugged for too long.
没有你我什么也不是
I'm nothing without you.
开始
Proceed.
你的身体退化太快
Your body's deteriorating
椅子会承受不住
faster than the chair can handle.
会撑过去的
It will survive long enough.
你真的打算让他们结婚
You're really going to let them get married?
没有爱  知识又是什么
What is knowledge without love?